Ra Mi-ran
را مي-ران
Lee Do-hyun
لي دو هيون
Ahn Eun-jin
آهن إيون-جين
Yoo In-soo
يو إن-سو
Sam-sik's Mill
مطحنة سام سيك
Choi Moo-sung - Jung Woong-in - Hong Bi-ra
تشوي مو سونغ - جونغ وونغ إن - هونغ بي را
Seo Yi-sook - Jang Won-young - Kang Mal-geum
Seo Yi-sook - Jang Won-young - Kang Mal-geum
Kim Won-hae - Park Bo-kyung
كيم وون هاي - بارك بو كيونج
Happy Farm
المزرعة السعيدة
The Good Bad Mother
الأم الطيبة السيئة
There are two animals...
هناك نوعان من الحيوانات...
that are useful from their head to toe.
مفيدة من الرأس إلى أخمص القدمين.
Do you know what they are?
هل تعرف ما هي؟
Humans...
البشر...
and pigs.
والخنازير.
Everyone thinks pigs are dirty and smelly,
يعتقد الجميع أن الخنازير قذرة وذات رائحة كريهة
but that's not the case.
لكن الأمر ليس كذلك.
Not only do their business in one place but they also only sleep where it's clean.
لا يقتصر الأمر على القيام بأعمالهم في مكان واحد لكنهم أيضًا لا ينامون إلا في الأماكن النظيفة.
They bathe often in mud to cool themselves,
غالبًا ما يستحمون في الوحل لتبريد أنفسهم
and get rid of bugs.
والتخلص من الأخطاء.
But humans started to lock them up in tiny pigsties.
لكن البشر بدأوا بالقفل لهم في الخنازير الصغيرة.
The pigs couldn't bathe in mud anymore,
لم تعد الخنازير قادرة على الاستحمام في الوحل بعد الآن
so they began to rub their bodies on their own excrement.
فبدأوا بفركهم الجثث على البراز الخاصة بهم.
That's how they grew dirtier and more aggressive.
وهذه هي الطريقة التي نشأوا بها أقذر وأكثر عدوانية.
Isn't that so sad?
أليس هذا محزنًا جدًا؟
The Good Bad Mother
الأم الطيبة السيئة
However, what's really sad is this.
ومع ذلك، فإن الأمر المحزن حقًا هو هذا.
Pigs are unable to lift their heads,
لا تستطيع الخنازير رفع رؤوسها
so they live their entire life staring at the ground.
لذا فهم يعيشون حياتهم بالكامل الحياة تحدق في الأرض.
There's only one way for a pig to look up at the sky.
هناك طريقة واحدة فقط ل خنزير للنظر إلى السماء.
It's...
إنه...
to fall down.
للسقوط.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Falling down...
السقوط...
is a way for you to see another world, a world you have never seen before,
هي طريقة تمكنك من رؤية عالم آخر، عالم لم تره من قبل،
both for pigs and people.
للخنازير والبشر على حد سواء.
I got you!
حصلت عليك!
Episode 1
الحلقة الأولى
♫ I'm happy ♫
♫ أنا سعيد ♫
♫ I'm very, very happy ♫
♫ أنا سعيد جدًا جدًا ♫
Joongang Feed & Supply
تغذية وتوريدات جونغانغ
Food delivery!
توصيل الطعام!
You were all gathered here.
لقد كنتم جميعاً مجتمعين هنا.
- Goodness! - Hello!
- الخير! - مرحبًا!
You're at it by yourself again.
أنت في ذلك بنفسك مرة أخرى.
- Thank you. - Sure.
- شكرًا لك. - بالتأكيد.
It's too heavy for a woman.
انها ثقيلة جدا بالنسبة للمرأة.
Goodness, sir.
الخير يا سيدي.
Goodness.
الخير.
Dog Feed, Cow Feed, Horse Feed Chicken Feed, Duck Feed, All Feeds
علف الكلاب، علف البقر، علف الحصان علف الدجاج، علف البط، جميع الأعلاف
Goodness. You're right.
الخير. أنت على حق.
It's too heavy for a woman.
انها ثقيلة جدا بالنسبة للمرأة.
Hey!
يا!
Delicious Feed For Cows
تغذية لذيذة للأبقار
Hi.
مرحبًا.
Young-soon!
يونغ قريبا!
Young-soon, take these with you.
يونغ-سون، خذ هذه معك.
Delicious Feed
خلاصة لذيذة
For Poultry
للدواجن
I'll give you the rest next month.
سأعطيك الباقي الشهر المقبل.
Goodness.
الخير.
- Thank you, Young-soon. - Sure.
- شكرا لك، يونغ قريبا. - بالتأكيد.
Here. These are fresh so it'll be delicious.
هنا. هذه طازجة لذا ستكون لذيذة.
- Thank you. - Drink up.
- شكرًا لك. - اشرب.
- Gosh, that's refreshing. - Give this to your boss.
- يا إلهي، هذا منعش. - أعط هذا لرئيسك.
Mulberries?
التوت؟
They're great for men.
إنها رائعة للرجال.
- Gosh, ma'am! - Gosh.
- يا إلهي سيدتي! - يا إلهي.
Joongang Feed & Supply
تغذية وتوريدات جونغانغ
This is nuts.
هذا هو المكسرات.
What's this?
ما هذا؟
That's red chili powder made with farm-grown peppers.
هذا مسحوق الفلفل الأحمر الحار مصنوعة من الفلفل المزروع في المزرعة.
To heck with that.
تبا لذلك.
Of course all red chili powders are from farms.
بالطبع جميع مساحيق الفلفل الأحمر تأتي من المزارع.
Then what about these?
فماذا عن هؤلاء؟
Were they assembled in a factory?
هل تم تجميعها في مصنع؟
Tell them to stop giving us these useless things,
اطلب منهم التوقف عن العطاء لنا هذه الأشياء عديمة الفائدة،
and pay us what they owe.
ويدفعون لنا ما عليهم.
I forgot.
لقد نسيت.
There are mulberries in the car.
يوجد توت في السيارة.
It's apparently great for men,
يبدو أنه رائع للرجال،
and Ms. Eun-ju from the goat farm told me to make sure you receive it.
والسيدة إيون جو من مزرعة الماعز قال لي للتأكد من حصولك عليه.
Ms. Eun-ju?
السيدة إيون جو؟
Why did she give me something...
لماذا أعطتني شيئا...
that's good for men?
هذا جيد للرجال؟
♫ Mulberry, where are you? ♫
♫ مولبيري، أين أنت؟ ♫
♫ Where are you? ♫
♫ أين أنت؟ ♫
♫ Where? ♫
♫ أين؟ ♫
They're both so obvious.
كلاهما واضح جدا.
Seriously.
بجد.
Welcome.
مرحباً.
Well, you must be busy.
حسنًا، لا بد أنك مشغول.
I...
أنا...
Are you going to a funeral?
هل أنت ذاهب إلى جنازة؟
No.
لا.
Well, Young-soon.
حسنًا، يونج سون.
She's pretty, isn't she?
إنها جميلة، أليس كذلك؟
She ate well this morning and...
لقد أكلت جيداً هذا الصباح و...
Young-soon.
يونغ قريبا.
Will you marry me?
هل ستتزوجني؟
Do a good job. Go.
قم بعمل جيد. يذهب.
Go to her.
اذهب إليها.
Go.
يذهب.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
These mulberries are sweet.
هذه التوت حلوة.
- Where are you going? - No!
- إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟ - لا!
- Hey, wait!
- مهلا، انتظر!
- Hey!
- يا!
- Get back here! - Goodness.
- عد إلى هنا! - الخير.
- Catch it! - Hey, piggy!
- قبض عليه! - مهلا، أصبع!
- What's that?
- ما هذا؟
- Goodness.
- الخير.
- It's running away! - Stop right there!
- إنه يهرب! - توقف هناك!
- Hey! - The pig!
- يا! - الخنزير!
Please catch the pig!
يرجى القبض على الخنزير!
The pig!
الخنزير!
A pig?
خنزير؟
- Hey, catch it. - Hey!
- مهلا، قبض عليه. - يا!
- Catch it!
- قبض عليه!
Hey, where are you going?
مهلا، إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
- Come here. - Catch it.
- تعال الى هنا. - قبض عليه.
Catch it!
قبض عليه!
You have to catch it!
عليك أن قبض عليه!
Go that way. Where did it go?
اذهب بهذه الطريقة. أين ذهبت؟
- Where did it go?
- أين ذهب؟
Rice pop!
رايس بوب!
- That scared me! - Are you okay?
- هذا أخافني! - هل أنت بخير؟
Have a good one.
أتمنى لك فكرة جيدة.
- There. - That scared me!
- هناك. - هذا أخافني!
- It was here. - A pig.
- كان هنا. - خنزير.
- Where? - It's a pig!
- أين؟ - إنه خنزير!
Over there!
هناك!
- Hey, come here! - Over here.
- مهلا، تعال هنا! - هنا.
- Where are you going? - No!
- إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟ - لا!
- Oh, no! - Can you catch that pig?
- أوه لا! - هل يمكنك التقاط هذا الخنزير؟
This way.
من هنا.
- Goodness. - Where?
- الخير. - أين؟
One more pork belly, please.
بطن لحم خنزير آخر، من فضلك.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
What's that noise?
ما هذا الضجيج؟
- Look. - What?
- ينظر. - ماذا؟
- What's that? - Oh, my!
- ما هذا؟ - يا بلدي!
- Goodness! - Wait.
- الخير! - انتظر.
- What's that? - Where are you?
- ما هذا؟ - أين أنت؟
I got it!
حصلت عليه!
Goodness.
الخير.
This little...!
هذا القليل...!
I don't want it.
أنا لا أريد ذلك.
They're having pork belly. Let's leave.
إنهم يتناولون بطن لحم الخنزير. دعونا نغادر.
Enjoy.
يتمتع.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
- What? - Go ahead and eat.
- ماذا؟ - تفضل وتناول الطعام.
- They caught it. - They did?
- قبضوا عليه. - فعلوا؟
- They did! - We did.
- لقد فعلوا! - لقد فعلنا.
- Good job! - Hey.
- أحسنت! - يا.
Young-soon, one second.
يونغ-سون، ثانية واحدة.
It didn't go as planned,
الأمر لم يسير كما خطط له،
but next time, I promise I'll train the pig better...
ولكن في المرة القادمة، أعدك سأقوم بتدريب الخنزير بشكل أفضل...
so it can go directly to you next time.
حتى يتمكن من الذهاب إليك مباشرة في المرة القادمة.
You're going to get married again?
هل ستتزوجين مرة أخرى؟
No, I'm not.
لا، أنا لست كذلك.
What are you talking about? I...
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟ أنا...
What?
ماذا؟
That means you'll...
يعني أنك سوف...
Thank you!
شكرا لك!
No wonder you always came to our shop when you had nothing to buy.
لا عجب أنك تأتي دائما لدينا تسوق عندما لم يكن لديك ما تشتريه.
Hey, wait!
مهلا، انتظر!
Does this mean you're going to quit?
هل هذا يعني أنك ستستقيل؟
No!
لا!
I don't approve of this marriage!
أنا لا أوافق على هذا الزواج!
- What do you mean? - It's off!
- ماذا تقصد؟ - انها خارج!
- It can't happen! - Move it.
- لا يمكن أن يحدث! - حركه.
I'll take a picture for you. Look over here.
سألتقط صورة لك. انظر هنا.
Goodness, you two are cute.
يا إلهي، أنتما لطيفان.
One, two, say piggy!
واحد، اثنان، قل أصبع!
The circuits look fine. Your electrical system looks good.
الدوائر تبدو جيدة. الخاص بك النظام الكهربائي يبدو جيدًا.
- Really? - Sparks are quite dangerous,
- حقًا؟ - الشرر خطير للغاية،
so make sure you dust often.
لذلك تأكد من الغبار في كثير من الأحيان.
Be careful when you spray water.
كن حذرا عند رش الماء.
All right. Thank you.
حسنًا. شكرًا لك.
No need to thank me. It's my job.
لا حاجة لشكري. إنها وظيفتي.
We're busy at the fire station...
نحن مشغولون في محطة الإطفاء...
- with frequent piggery fires. - I see.
- مع حرائق الخنازير المتكررة. - أرى.
I'll stop by next time I'm on patrol.
سأتوقف في المرة القادمة التي أقوم فيها بدورية.
Hold on.
يتمسك.
Take this.
خذ هذا.
I heard your baby just turned 1!
سمعت أن طفلك بلغ للتو عامه الأول!
Your father told me.
قال لي والدك.
- Buy your kid some clothes. - Goodness, it's okay.
- اشتري لابنك بعض الملابس. - الخير، لا بأس.
I couldn't even go to your wedding.
لم أتمكن حتى من الذهاب إلى حفل زفافك.
Don't say that.
لا تقل ذلك.
I know you spend all your weekends with your mother at the hospital.
أعلم أنك تقضي كل عطلات نهاية الأسبوع مع والدتك في المستشفى.
If it bothers you that much,
إذا كان الأمر يزعجك إلى هذا الحد،
you can come to my kid's first birthday.
يمكنك أن تأتي إلى عيد ميلاد طفلي الأول.
What? That means...
ماذا؟ وهذا يعني...
I'm going to be a dad!
انا ذاهب ليكون أبا!
- Congratulations! - My heart is racing!
- تهانينا! - قلبي يتسابق!
My gosh. Isn't this great?
يا إلهي. أليس هذا عظيما؟
When is the baby due?
متى يحين موعد الطفل؟
Next September, the Year of the Dragon.
سبتمبر المقبل هو عام التنين.
It's the Year of the Double Dragon in the year '88...
إنها سنة المزدوج التنين في عام 88...
that only comes around once every 300 years.
والذي يأتي مرة واحدة فقط كل 300 عام.
Look at this.
أنظر إلى هذا.
I want to give my kid the best name,
أريد أن أعطي طفلي أفضل إسم
so I've been studying this.
لذلك كنت أدرس هذا.
Kang-cheol.
كانغ تشيول.
Kang-su.
كانغ سو.
Kang-jun.
كانغ جون.
Kang is the generational syllable.
كانغ هو مقطع الأجيال.
Kang-hun.
كانغ هون.
Kang-sik.
كانغ سيك.
- Kang-min. - What if the baby's a girl?
- كانغ مين. - وماذا لو كان الطفل فتاة؟
Kang-hui. Kang-sun.
كانغ هوي. كانغ سون.
Kang-ja.
كانغ جا.
Kang-mi.
كانغ مي.
Hey, I'm prepared for everything.
ها أنا مستعد لكل شيء.
And look at this too.
وانظر إلى هذا أيضًا.
Ta-da.
تا دا.
I don't know if it'll be a boy or a girl, so I got both.
لا أعرف ما إذا كان سيكون صبي أو فتاة، لذلك حصلت على كليهما.
Bongu Farm
مزرعة بونغو
The baby's not due for a while, and you're already studying names.
الطفل لن يأتي لفترة من الوقت، وأنت تدرس الأسماء بالفعل.
You must be very excited.
يجب أن تكون متحمسًا جدًا.
Of course I am!
بالطبع أنا!
Anyway, why does it take ten months for humans?
على أية حال، لماذا يستغرق الإنسان عشرة أشهر؟
Why can't humans give birth in four months like pigs?
لماذا لا يستطيع الإنسان الإنجاب؟ في أربعة أشهر مثل الخنازير؟
Right?
يمين؟
I'll also think of a good name...
سأفكر أيضًا في اسم جيد ...
- that begins with "Kang." - No, don't.
- الذي يبدأ بـ "كانغ". - لا، لا تفعل ذلك.
You don't need to.
لا تحتاج إلى ذلك.
I'm going to do it.
انا ذاهب للقيام بذلك.
Don't dare name my kid, okay?
لا تجرؤ على تسمية طفلي، حسنًا؟
Thanks, Sang-cheol. Bye.
شكرا، سانغ تشيول. الوداع.
Bye now.
وداعاً الآن.
All right.
حسنًا.
Yong-yong, my Double Dragon.
يونغ يونغ، التنين المزدوج.
Daddy made this.
بابا صنع هذا.
Yong-yong
يونج يونج
This is all for you.
هذا كل شيء بالنسبة لك.
Hae-sik!
هاي سيك!
- Hae-sik. - Yes?
- هاي سيك. - نعم؟
- I need you at the breeding house. - Why?
- أحتاجك في بيت التربية. - لماذا؟
She's doing it again.
إنها تفعل ذلك مرة أخرى.
- Again? - Yes.
- مرة أخرى؟ - نعم.
Okay. Let's go.
تمام. دعنا نذهب.
Hey, piggy. Doesn't it hurt?
مهلا، أصبع. لا يضر؟
What makes you so miserable that you bang your head?
ما الذي يجعلك بائسة جدا أن تضرب رأسك؟
Think of the babies in your womb.
فكر في الأطفال في رحمك.
You shouldn't do that as a mother.
لا يجب أن تفعلي ذلك كأم.
- Here you are. - Hey, you're here.
- تفضل. - مهلا، أنت هنا.
She did it again.
لقد فعلت ذلك مرة أخرى.
The Ministry of Home Affairs began environmental improvement projects...
بدأت وزارة الداخلية مشاريع تحسين البيئة...
to take a leap into developed nations.
للقفز إلى الدول المتقدمة.
More resources have been allocated to paving local roads...
تم توفير المزيد من الموارد مخصصة لرصف الطرق المحلية...
to complete the project before the Seoul Olympics,
لإكمال المشروع قبل أولمبياد سيول،
- hastening the process. - It's so good.
- تسريع العملية. - انها جيدة جدا.
Our baby is probably only tiny,
ربما يكون طفلنا صغيرًا فقط،
but I'm already feeling morning sickness.
لكني أشعر بالفعل بغثيان الصباح.
But that mother pig carries ten piglets.
لكن تلك الخنزيرة الأم تحمل عشرة خنازير.
It must be so tough.
يجب أن تكون صعبة للغاية.
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
But I'm worried she'll stress out...
لكني أخشى أنها ستتوتر..
the other mother pigs.
الخنازير الأم الأخرى.
It's a sensitive time, and they need to stay healthy.
إنه وقت حساس، وهم بحاجة إلى البقاء بصحة جيدة.
Why don't you separate them?
لماذا لا تفصل بينهما؟
Our storage is empty.
مخزننا فارغ.
Should I do that?
هل يجب أن أفعل ذلك؟
I'll make a pigsty,
سأصنع حظيرة للخنازير،
feed it every day, and look after it.
أطعمه كل يوم، واعتني به.
Nonsense! You're in early pregnancy.
هراء! أنت في بداية الحمل.
You need to be the most careful right now.
عليك أن تكون الأكثر حذراً الآن.
Don't strain yourself. Don't even do this.
لا ترهق نفسك. لا تفعل هذا حتى.
I'll do everything.
سأفعل كل شيء.
- I'm fine. - No.
- أنا بخير. - لا.
It's for our Yong-yong.
إنها من أجل يونج يونج.
Let's see what our baby is up to.
دعونا نرى ما يفعله طفلنا.
- My gosh. - One second.
- يا إلهي. - ثانية واحدة.
Yong-yong.
يونغ يونغ.
We're going to have a chat today.
سنجري محادثة اليوم.
Here.
هنا.
Yong-yong, respond, over.
يونغ يونغ، أجب، انتهى.
Can you say "Daddy"?
هل يمكنك أن تقول "بابا"؟
Say "Daddy."
قل "أبي".
I just heard our baby say it. I mean it.
لقد سمعت للتو طفلنا يقول ذلك. أعني ذلك.
- One second. - I can't believe you.
- ثانية واحدة. - لا أستطيع أن أصدقك.
What?
ماذا؟
I see.
أرى.
I have to do that now?
يجب أن أفعل ذلك الآن؟
I have to give Mommy a big kiss?
هل يجب أن أعطي أمي قبلة كبيرة؟
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Oh, my.
يا بلدي.
You might have another child before that one's born.
قد يكون لديك آخر طفل قبل أن يولد ذلك الشخص.
Chief.
رئيس.
Is our doorbell broken?
هل جرس بابنا مكسور؟
- Have some of this. - Hello.
- هل لديك بعض من هذا. - مرحبًا.
- Have a mung bean pancake. - Goodness.
- تناول فطيرة فول مونج. - الخير.
I can get a treat like this, now that you have a wife.
يمكنني الحصول على علاج مثل هذا، الآن بعد أن أصبح لديك زوجة.
This is really good.
هذا جيد حقا.
Right? Isn't it great?
يمين؟ أليس هذا رائعا؟
Anyway, what brings you here, Chief?
على أية حال، ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا أيها الرئيس؟
I have something to discuss with you.
لدي شيء لأناقشه معك.
- I see. - You know...
- أرى. - تعلمين...
about the Olympics torch relay, right?
بخصوص تتابع شعلة الألعاب الأولمبية، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, I know.
نعم أنا أعلم.
For the Seoul Olympics,
بالنسبة لأولمبياد سيول،
the relay will go through Bongu-ro and right out front.
سوف يمر التتابع Bongu-ro ومباشرة في الخارج.
- Right here? - Really?
- هنا؟ - حقًا؟
What an honor.
يا له من شرف.
Does this mean we get to see the torch relay live?
هل هذا يعني أننا حصلنا على لرؤية تتابع الشعلة على الهواء مباشرة؟
That's why I thought of gathering the villagers...
لهذا السبب فكرت جمع أهل القرية...
to cheer the runners with Korean flags and banners.
ليهتف المتسابقين مع الأعلام واللافتات الكورية.
That sounds great.
هذا يبدو عظيما.
That's a wonderful idea.
هذه فكرة رائعة.
Then may I make the flags and banners?
إذن هل لي أن أصنع الأعلام واللافتات؟
I'm a good artist.
أنا فنان جيد.
Honey, you shouldn't strain yourself.
عزيزي، لا يجب أن تجهد نفسك.
Strain myself? This is all for our country.
أجهد نفسي؟ هذا كل شيء من أجل بلدنا.
May I do that?
هل يمكنني أن أفعل ذلك؟
Of course!
بالطبع!
- I'd be grateful! - No, you can't.
- سأكون ممتنا! - لا، لا يمكنك ذلك.
Come on.
تعال.
Wishing for a Successful Olympics Welcome to Bongu-dong
أتمنى نجاح الألعاب الأولمبية مرحبًا بك في Bongu-dong
♫ I will ♫
♫ سأفعل ♫
♫ love forever ♫
♫ الحب إلى الأبد ♫
So what is this?
إذن ما هذا؟
You're going to demolish my farm...
سوف تهدم مزرعتي..
because of the torch relay?
بسبب تتابع الشعلة؟
That's just one of the reasons.
هذا مجرد أحد الأسباب.
The marathon will also be held down this road.
وسيقام الماراثون أيضًا على هذا الطريق.
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
The whole world will watch it on TV.
العالم كله سوف يشاهده على شاشة التلفزيون.
If the TV captures this dirty, smelly pigsty,
إذا صور التلفزيون هذا الخنزير القذر ذو الرائحة الكريهة،
foreigners are going to think Korea is a backwater country.
سوف يفكر الأجانب كوريا بلد منعزل.
- Don't you think so? - Hey.
- ألا تعتقد ذلك؟ - يا.
We're all doing this out of patriotism.
كلنا نفعل ذلك بدافع الوطنية.
- Honey.
- عسل.
- Look. - That's a good one.
- ينظر. - هذا فكرة جيدة.
Who are they?
من هم؟
Nobody. Go back inside.
لا أحد. العودة إلى الداخل.
We have to get to work.
علينا أن نبدأ العمل.
We're busy, so please leave.
نحن مشغولون، لذا يرجى المغادرة.
- Don't push me. - No, please go.
- لا تدفعني. - لا، من فضلك اذهب.
Please leave now.
يرجى المغادرة الآن.
How dare you lay a hand on me?
كيف تجرؤ على وضع يدك علي؟
- What are you doing? Let go! - No!
- ماذا تفعل؟ اتركه! - لا!
- Let go, you jerks! - What are you people doing?
- اتركوا أيها الحمقى! - ماذا تفعلون أيها الناس؟
Go back inside.
العودة إلى الداخل.
- Who do you think you are? - Let go!
- من تظن نفسك؟ - اتركه!
Quiet down!
هادئ!
Gosh.
يا إلهي.
I told you to explain it to him quietly and with respect.
قلت لك أن تشرح ذلك ل له بهدوء واحترام.
What are you doing right now?
ماذا تفعل الآن؟
What are you doing, you punk?
ماذا تفعل يا فاسق؟
Darn it.
الرتق.
Goodness, I'm sorry.
الخير، أنا آسف.
All he's ever done is fight.
كل ما فعله هو القتال.
He's not educated.
انه ليس متعلما.
Well...
حسنا...
Take this.
خذ هذا.
So...
لذا...
Have you heard of Major League Baseball in the U.S.?
هل سمعت عن الرائد دوري البيسبول في الولايات المتحدة؟
Director Song Woo-byeok
المخرج سونغ وو بايوك
The best pitcher on the Boston Red Sox,
أفضل إبريق في بوسطن ريد سوكس،
Roger Clemens smokes these.
روجر كليمنس يدخن هذه.
We may be able to import Patriot missiles,
قد نتمكن من استيراد صواريخ باتريوت،
but these are really tough to bring into the country.
ولكن هذه صعبة حقا لجلب إلى البلاد.
Please have a smoke...
من فضلك دخن..
and forgive us.
واغفر لنا.
You smoke foreign cigarettes,
أنت تدخن السجائر الأجنبية،
and talk about patriotism?
ويتحدثون عن الوطنية؟
I don't care if it's the torch relay or the marathon.
لا يهمني إذا كان تتابع الشعلة أو الماراثون.
Even at a snail's pace, our farm will be on TV for less than 30 seconds.
حتى بوتيرة الحلزون، مزرعتنا سيكون على شاشة التلفزيون لمدة تقل عن 30 ثانية.
And the smell?
والرائحة؟
Do TVs abroad broadcast smells?
هل تبث أجهزة التلفاز في الخارج الروائح؟
We've run this farm for generations,
لقد قمنا بإدارة هذه المزرعة لأجيال،
since the days of my grandfather's grandfather.
منذ أيام جد جدي.
I'm going to leave it to my son,
سأترك الأمر لابني،
and to his grandson and his grandson too!
وحفيده وحفيده أيضا!
So I'll never sign this form!
لذلك لن أوقع هذا النموذج أبدًا!
Don't ever come back here.
لا تعود إلى هنا أبدًا.
Understand?
يفهم؟
You must be shocked. Let's go inside.
يجب أن تصاب بالصدمة. دعنا نذهب إلى الداخل.
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
Eat up and get well soon,
تناول الطعام والشفاء قريبا ،
so you'll have a healthy delivery.
لذلك سيكون لديك ولادة صحية.
Yes.
نعم.
I'm glad we put her in the storage.
أنا سعيد لأننا وضعناها في المخزن.
- Right. - She's much calmer now.
- يمين. - إنها أكثر هدوءا الآن.
You're right.
أنت على حق.
So Chief, no matter how important the Olympics is,
لذا أيها الرئيس، مهما كانت الطريقة المهم الأولمبياد هو
these are lawfully our personal assets.
هذه هي أصولنا الشخصية بشكل قانوني.
What can they do about it? We have to hold out no matter what.
ماذا يمكنهم أن يفعلوا حيال ذلك؟ نحن يجب أن تصمد مهما حدث.
We should put together an anti-demolition committee...
يجب علينا أن نجمع معًا لجنة مكافحة الهدم..
and fight until the end, okay?
والقتال حتى النهاية، حسنا؟
I won't condone this.
لن أتغاضى عن هذا.
I'll meet with an attorney right away.
سأقابل محاميًا على الفور.
Yes, I'll call you later. Bye.
نعم، سأتصل بك لاحقا. الوداع.
Goodness, look at the time.
يا إلهي، انظر إلى الوقت.
- I have to feed the pigs. - Hey.
- لا بد لي من إطعام الخنازير. - يا.
Honey.
عسل.
I already fed the pigs.
لقد أطعمت الخنازير بالفعل.
- You did? - Yes.
- فعلت؟ - نعم.
Why did you do that? It's tough on you.
لماذا فعلت ذلك؟ انها صعبة عليك.
Things are tougher for you.
الأمور أصعب بالنسبة لك.
Honey.
عسل.
Don't worry about it.
لا تقلق بشأن هذا
You know me, right? I'll never give up.
أنت تعرفني، أليس كذلك؟ لن أستسلم أبدًا.
I won't lose.
لن أخسر.
Do you know why?
هل تعرف لماذا؟
Look, I got you right here,
انظر، لقد حصلت عليك هنا،
and I got Yong-yong here too!
وأنا حصلت على يونغ يونغ هنا أيضا!
How can I lose to anybody?
كيف يمكن أن أخسر أمام أي شخص؟
Everything will be fine.
كل شيء سيكون على ما يرام.
- Fire!
- النار! - نار!
- There's a fire!
- هناك حريق!
- Over there!
- هناك!
Honey.
عسل.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Honey!
عسل!
What? What's going on?
ماذا؟ ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Where's the fire?
أين النار؟
Oh, no! Call the firehouse!
أوه لا! استدعاء المطافئ!
Where's the firetruck?
أين عربة الإطفاء؟
- No!
- لا!
- You can't go in!
- لا يمكنك الدخول!
- I have to go in! - Don't go!
- لا بد لي من الدخول! - لا تذهب!
- Let go! - No, you can't!
- اتركه! - لا، لا يمكنك!
- Goodness, no! - Goodness!
- الخير، لا! - الخير!
- No! - Let go!
- لا! - اتركه!
My pigs are dying in there! This isn't right!
خنازيري تموت هناك! هذا ليس صحيحا!
Even pigs don't deserve to die like this!
حتى الخنازير لا تستحق أن تموت هكذا!
No!
لا!
Honey, I'm sorry.
العسل، أنا آسف.
But you can't go in there.
لكن لا يمكنك الدخول إلى هناك.
I can't let you go in there.
لا أستطيع السماح لك بالدخول إلى هناك.
Why?
لماذا؟
Why?!
لماذا؟!
I saw it with my own two eyes.
رأيت ذلك بعيني.
I came out to take a leak earlier,
لقد خرجت لأخذ تسرب في وقت سابق،
and I heard the dogs barking,
و سمعت الكلاب تنبح
and saw some dark figures lurking around.
ورأيت بعض الشخصيات المظلمة تتربص حولها.
I kept watching to see who they were,
ظللت أراقب لأرى من هم،
and they were those punks from Yongra Construction.
وكانوا هؤلاء الأشرار من شركة يونجرا للإنشاءات.
I wondered why they were here in the middle of the night,
تساءلت لماذا كانوا كذلك هنا في منتصف الليل،
then I suddenly saw these flames.
ثم فجأة رأيت هذه النيران.
See?
يرى؟
- I told you it'd be them. - Are you sure?
- قلت لك أنه سيكون منهم. - هل أنت متأكد؟
- Are you sure it was them? - Yes!
- هل أنت متأكد من أنهم كانوا؟ - نعم!
Honey.
عسل.
- Honey. - Look at this.
- عسل. - أنظر إلى هذا.
It's the American brand that man was smoking, right?
إنها العلامة التجارية الأمريكية ذلك الرجل كان يدخن، أليس كذلك؟
Evidence 1
الدليل 1
You're right.
أنت على حق.
That's the same brand as the ones I smoke.
هذه نفس العلامة التجارية التي أدخنها.
Is that a problem?
هل هذه مشكلة؟
These cigarettes are only sold in the U.S.,
هذه السجائر تباع فقط في الولايات المتحدة،
and they've never been imported here.
ولم يتم استيرادها هنا أبدًا.
Which means it's not easy for ordinary people to buy these.
مما يعني أنه ليس من السهل عليه الناس العاديين لشراء هذه.
However, this cigarette butt was found near the victim's farm,
ومع ذلك، هذا بعقب السجائر تم العثور عليها بالقرب من مزرعة الضحية،
who recently had a dispute with the defendant over the demolition.
الذي كان لديه نزاع مؤخرا مع المدعى عليه في عملية الهدم.
It means there's a high possibility this cigarette belongs to the defendant.
يعني هناك احتمال كبير هذه السيجارة تعود للمتهم.
Well, Mr. Kim of Daeil Real Estate.
حسنًا، السيد كيم من شركة دعيل العقارية.
Me?
أنا؟
When I first went to see you, I gave you a cigarette, didn't I?
عندما ذهبت لرؤيتك لأول مرة، لقد أعطيتك سيجارة، أليس كذلك؟
I didn't smoke it.
لم أدخنه.
I also gave one to the radio shop owner.
وأعطيت واحدة أيضًا لصاحب متجر الراديو.
And the village chief too.
ورئيس القرية أيضا.
Chief, you got one too.
أيها الرئيس، لديك واحدة أيضاً.
I smoked it that day!
لقد دخنته في ذلك اليوم!
- Silence. - Who knows?
- الصمت. - من يدري؟
What?
ماذا؟
Are you saying I started the fire?
هل تقول أنني أشعلت النار؟
I said, silence!
قلت: الصمت!
Witness
الشاهد
Well, yes, I did see something.
حسنًا، نعم، لقد رأيت شيئًا ما.
But come to think of it, I'm not sure if it was a man or a boar.
ولكن عندما تفكر في الأمر، أنا لست كذلك تأكد إذا كان رجلاً أو خنزيرًا.
Right, maybe a wild dog.
صحيح، ربما كلب بري.
Yes, you're right.
نعم، أنت على حق.
We had to repaint the roof,
كان علينا أن نعيد طلاء السقف
but recently it kept raining,
ولكن في الآونة الأخيرة استمر هطول الأمطار،
so we kept the buckets of paint and thinner inside the farm.
لذلك احتفظنا بالدلاء دهان ومنحف داخل المزرعة .
We only had two buckets!
لم يكن لدينا سوى دلوين!
But more than five buckets were at the scene!
ولكن كان هناك أكثر من خمسة دلاء في مكان الحادث!
This was clearly arson!
كان من الواضح أن هذا حريق متعمد!
Silence!
الصمت!
There's a better chance that the cause was a short circuit than arson.
هناك فرصة أفضل أن كان السبب ماس كهربائي من الحرق العمد.
Actually,
في الواقع،
there were a lot of problems with the electrical system at the farm.
كان هناك الكثير من المشاكل مع النظام الكهربائي في المزرعة.
I urged him to get it fixed, but he never took adequate measures.
وحثته على إصلاح الأمر، لكنه لم يتخذ التدابير الكافية قط.
Hey, Sang-cheol! What's with you?
مهلا، سانغ تشيول! ماذا بك؟
Silence!
الصمت!
Sang-cheol...
سانغ تشيول...
It's difficult to acknowledge the cigarette butt as evidence...
من الصعب الاعتراف بذلك عقب السيجارة كدليل..
purely on the presumption of the prosecution.
محض على افتراض النيابة.
Also, no witnesses or tools of arson were found to support the claim...
كما لا يوجد شهود أو أدوات للحرق العمد تم العثور على دعم لهذا الادعاء ...
that the defendant started the fire.
أن المتهم أشعل النار.
For such reasons,
لمثل هذه الأسباب،
the indictment is ruled as not credible.
حكم على لائحة الاتهام بأنها غير موثوقة.
The defendant is innocent.
المتهم بريء.
That's right!
هذا صحيح!
Hey, Sang-cheol.
مهلا، سانغ تشيول.
Hae-sik.
هاي سيك.
I have something to say.
لدي شيء لأقوله.
- Stay away from me. - Sang-cheol.
- ابتعد عني. - سانغ تشيول.
- It's not that. - Don't come near me!
- ليس هذا. - لا تقترب مني!
Sang-cheol!
سانغ تشيول!
I needed money for my mother's surgery.
كنت بحاجة إلى المال لإجراء عملية جراحية لوالدتي.
They said no matter how much you hold out and resist,
قالوا مهما كانت الطريقة كثيرًا ما تصمد وتقاوم،
it'll be over once the state decides to bulldoze the pig farm.
سوف ينتهي الأمر بمجرد انتهاء الولاية يقرر هدم مزرعة الخنازير.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Hae-sik.
هاي-سيك.
They knew my daughter's home address,
كانوا يعرفون عنوان منزل ابنتي
and where she works.
وأين تعمل.
What would you have done?
ماذا كنت ستفعل؟
That must've been tough.
لا بد أن ذلك كان صعبًا.
This is enough evidence to file an appeal.
وهذا دليل كافي لتقديم الاستئناف.
I see.
أرى.
Prosecutor Oh, I'm meeting TV reporters...
المدعي العام أوه، أنا أقابل مراسلي التلفزيون...
and international reporters tomorrow.
والمراسلين الدوليين غدا.
- Reporters? - Yes.
- مراسلون؟ - نعم.
I asked around,
سألت من حولي
and that Director Song...
وأغنية المخرج تلك...
is apparently the heir to Yongra Construction.
يبدو أنه وريث شركة Yongra Construction.
And I found many suspicious incidents.
ووجدت العديد من الحوادث المشبوهة.
There were many incidents of fire on demolition sites...
كانت هناك حوادث كثيرة حريق في مواقع الهدم..
where Director Song was in charge.
حيث كان المخرج سونغ هو المسؤول.
Although most incidents were concluded as short-circuit fires,
على الرغم من أن معظم الحوادث كانت وانتهت على شكل حرائق دائرة كهربائية قصيرة،
many details were unclear.
العديد من التفاصيل كانت غير واضحة.
Strangely enough,
ومن الغريب أن
witnesses and investigators all changed their testimonies.
الشهود والمحققين كلهم غيروا شهاداتهم.
Doesn't it sound similar to our case?
ألا يبدو الأمر مشابهًا لحالتنا؟
Well...
حسنا...
Prosecutor Oh.
المدعي العام اه.
Here.
هنا.
I've been saving up some money...
لقد قمت بتوفير بعض المال...
to build a new home when our baby is born.
لبناء منزل جديد عندما يولد طفلنا.
I don't want my child to be ridiculed...
لا أريد أن يتعرض طفلي للسخرية...
for living in a smelly home next to a pig farm.
للعيش في منزل ذو رائحة كريهة بجوار مزرعة خنازير.
But Prosecutor Oh,
لكن المدعي العام أوه،
I'd feel more shame...
سأشعر بالخجل أكثر..
to live as a helpless father who let those jerks have their way,
ليعيش كأب عاجز الذي فليأخذ هؤلاء الحمقى طريقهم،
than to stink like a pigsty.
من أن نتن مثل الخنازير.
It doesn't matter how much it costs.
لا يهم كم يكلف.
Prosecutor Oh.
المدعي العام اه.
Please reveal the truth.
يرجى الكشف عن الحقيقة.
But the money...
لكن المال...
Prosecutor Oh, I...
المدعي العام: أنا...
I understand for now.
أفهم الآن.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
3 Years, 10 Night Fires
3 سنوات، 10 حرائق ليلية
I'm counting on you, sir.
أنا أعول عليك يا سيدي.
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
This is Oh Tae-soo.
هذا هو أوه تاي سو.
Things have become troublesome.
لقد أصبحت الأمور مزعجة.
♫ I'm happy ♫
♫ أنا سعيد ♫
♫ I'm very, very happy ♫
♫ أنا سعيد جدًا جدًا ♫
Car trouble?
مشكلة السيارة؟
Bongu Farm
مزرعة بونغو
Excuse me, could you move?
عفوا، هل يمكنك التحرك؟
Have a drink.
تناول مشروب.
One for me.
واحد بالنسبة لي.
I was watching baseball yesterday,
كنت أشاهد البيسبول بالأمس،
and the game was completely ridiculous.
وكانت اللعبة سخيفة تمامًا.
I mean,
أعني،
if the fielders got hold of the ball,
إذا استحوذ اللاعبون على الكرة،
the runner should've stopped at second or third base.
كان ينبغي للعداء أن يتوقف في القاعدة الثانية أو الثالثة.
This idiot got greedy and tried to make it to home plate.
هذا الغبي أصبح جشعا و حاولت الوصول إلى لوحة المنزل.
And he was tagged out.
وقد تم وضع علامة عليه.
Gosh, that idiot.
يا إلهي، هذا الأحمق.
Baseball...
البيسبول...
is exactly like life.
هو تماما مثل الحياة.
What's important isn't running, but knowing when to stop.
المهم ليس الجري ولكن معرفة متى تتوقف.
And you also need to know where to stop.
وتحتاج أيضًا إلى معرفة مكان التوقف.
Anyway.
على أي حال.
Everything...
كل شيء...
is in the past.
في الماضي.
Mr. Choi, have a drink...
سيد تشوي، تناول مشروبًا...
and forget all about it.
وننسى كل شيء عن ذلك.
All right then.
حسنًا إذن.
Here. You can eat this on your way.
هنا. يمكنك أن تأكل هذا في طريقك.
If he stepped on the chair to get up...
إذا صعد على الكرسي ليقوم..
Good, right?
جيد، أليس كذلك؟
No, it should be knocked over.
لا، يجب أن يتم إسقاطه.
That looks more natural, right?
يبدو ذلك أكثر طبيعية، أليس كذلك؟
All done. Let's go.
تم كل شيء. دعنا نذهب.
Boys, move. Let's hurry.
أيها الأولاد، تحركوا. دعونا نسرع.
- Grab the glass. - Yes.
- الاستيلاء على الزجاج. - نعم.
All right.
حسنًا.
Yong-yong
يونج يونج
Honey?
العسل؟
Honey, what happened?
عزيزي ماذا حدث؟
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Let's go home.
دعنا نذهب إلى المنزل.
Let's just give them the farm. Let's let them have it all.
دعونا فقط نعطيهم المزرعة. دعونا نسمح لهم بالحصول على كل شيء.
- Let's just go home, Honey. - Ma'am.
- دعنا نعود للمنزل يا عزيزتي . - سيدتي.
- Let's go! - Please calm down.
- دعنا نذهب! - يرجى تهدئة.
I'll give you everything.
سأعطيك كل شيء.
I'll give you everything!
سأعطيك كل شيء!
Please save my husband!
أرجوك أنقذ زوجي!
No!
لا!
You can have everything!
يمكنك الحصول على كل شيء!
Prosecutor Oh Tae-soo?
المدعي العام أوه تاي سو؟
Yes?
نعم؟
I brought the car you sent for repair.
أحضرت السيارة التي أرسلتها للإصلاح.
The trunk is fully cleaned out too. Please check.
يتم تنظيف الجذع بالكامل خارج جدا. يرجى المراجعة.
Excuse me. Hey!
اعذرني. يا!
Are you Prosecutor Oh Tae-soo?
هل أنت المدعي العام أوه تاي سو؟
Yes, hello.
نعم مرحبا.
He said he found important evidence,
وقال إنه وجد أدلة مهمة،
and he was going to meet with reporters.
وكان سيلتقي بالمراسلين.
So why would he kill himself?
فلماذا يقتل نفسه؟
And look at this.
وانظر إلى هذا.
Isn't this weird?
أليس هذا غريبا؟
The scar on his neck is too smooth.
الندبة الموجودة على رقبته ناعمة للغاية.
Even if he was determined to die,
حتى لو كان مصمماً على الموت،
there should be some trace of struggling due to pain, right?
يجب أن يكون هناك بعض الأثر من النضال بسبب الألم، أليس كذلك؟
Bank Book
دفتر البنك
After hearing what you just said,
بعد سماع ما قلته للتو،
I'm convinced he killed himself.
أنا مقتنع أنه قتل نفسه.
If he found important evidence,
إذا وجد أدلة مهمة،
why didn't he bring it to me?
لماذا لم يحضره لي؟
Instead, he stopped by, drunk, and said he wanted to kill himself,
وبدلاً من ذلك، توقف هناك، وهو في حالة سكر، وقال أنه يريد أن يقتل نفسه،
and that if anything happened to him,
وأنه إذا حدث له أي شيء
I should give this bank book to you.
يجب أن أعطيك دفتر البنك هذا.
He was quite drunk and persistent.
لقد كان في حالة سكر للغاية ومثابرًا.
So I took it...
لذلك أخذته...
and told him to go home.
وأخبرته أن يذهب إلى المنزل.
I didn't know he'd end up like this.
لم أكن أعلم أنه سينتهي هكذا.
Why did he do that?
لماذا فعل ذلك؟
Bank Book
دفتر البنك
How frustrated and lost must he have been to do something like that?
كم هو محبط وخسر وقد تم القيام بشيء من هذا القبيل؟
I should've done...
كان يجب أن أفعل...
everything I could to keep him safe.
كل ما بوسعي للحفاظ على سلامته.
I should've...
كان يجب علي...
supported him...
دعمته...
and helped him better.
وساعده بشكل أفضل.
But I don't know anything, and I don't have anything.
لكني لا أعرف شيئًا، وليس لدي أي شيء.
One thing I do have is...
شيء واحد لدي هو...
I won't...
لن...
let this child live like us.
دع هذا الطفل يعيش مثلنا.
I'll live.
سأعيش.
Let's live.
دعونا نعيش.
Both my baby...
كلا يا طفلي...
and your babies...
وأطفالك...
must've come to save their mothers.
لا بد وأنهم جاءوا لإنقاذ أمهاتهم.
So...
لذا...
let's...
دعونا...
not give up,
لا تستسلم،
and live.
ويعيش.
I used to sell feed to this farm,
كنت أبيع الأعلاف لهذه المزرعة
but it closed two years ago.
لكنها أغلقت منذ عامين.
I'm only letting you know because it's you, Young-soon.
أنا فقط أعلمك لأنه أنت، يونج سون.
It's tough to find a farm and a home within your budget.
من الصعب العثور على مزرعة و منزل في حدود ميزانيتك.
Jou-ri Doldam Village Welcome
قرية جو ري دولدام مرحبًا
Bongu Farm
مزرعة بونجو
Breeding Information
معلومات التربية
They all look healthy.
كلهم يبدون بصحة جيدة.
All nine of them. Goodness.
كل تسعة منهم. الخير.
"If the building set on fire..."
"إذا اشتعلت النيران في المبنى ..."
"is used as a residence at the time of the fire,"
"يستخدم كمسكن في وقت الحريق"
"or if people are in..."
"أو إذا كان الناس في ..."
Happy Farm
المزرعة السعيدة
Are those pigs?
هل تلك الخنازير؟
Pigs in our pristine village?
الخنازير في قريتنا البكر؟
Our village is clean and unspoiled!
قريتنا نظيفة وغير ملوثة!
Goodness, we have pigs here!
يا إلهي، لدينا خنازير هنا!
Why pigs?
لماذا الخنازير؟
Stay still. Calm down.
ابق ساكنا. اهدأ.
- Why are those pigs here? - What?
- لماذا تلك الخنازير هنا؟ - ماذا؟
Pigs are here!
الخنازير هنا!
- Yes, but why are they here? - Why...?
- نعم، ولكن لماذا هم هنا؟ - لماذا...؟
Look, Honey.
انظر يا عزيزتي.
Didn't I do a good job by myself?
ألم أقم بعمل جيد بنفسي؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Our child kicked me...
ركلني طفلنا...
to remind me I'm not alone.
ليذكرني أنني لست وحدي.
I'll raise our child well...
سأربي طفلنا جيدًا...
to get our revenge on you for leaving us.
للانتقام منك لأنك تركتنا.
So Honey, keep an eye on us from above.
لذا عزيزتي، راقبينا من الأعلى.
I mean.
أعني.
Watch over us.
احترس منا.
No Trespassing
ممنوع التعدي على ممتلكات الغير
The air was so fresh for the last two years,
كان الهواء منعشًا للغاية خلال العامين الماضيين،
but we have to put up with this nonsense again.
ولكن علينا أن نتحمل هذا الهراء مرة أخرى.
We can't just talk this out.
لا يمكننا أن نتحدث عن هذا فحسب.
We should just wipe out the entire farm.
يجب علينا فقط محو المزرعة بأكملها.
- Goodness, hey... Oh, my. - Oh, my.
- يا إلهي...يا إلهي. - يا بلدي.
- Goodness, ma'am. - Mother.
- الخير يا سيدتي. - الأم.
- Are you all right? - I'm fine.
- هل أنت بخير؟ - أنا بخير.
Ma'am, you, the kid, and the ladies should...
سيدتي، أنت، الطفل، والسيدات يجب أن...
all stay out of this.
كل البقاء خارج هذا.
The men will take care of everything.
الرجال سوف يعتنون بكل شيء.
So you were a man?
إذن كنت رجلاً؟
What have you done up to now,
ماذا فعلت حتى الآن،
as President of the Young Adult Association?
كرئيس لجمعية الشباب؟
Goodness gracious.
رباه.
Then what have you done as President of the Women's Association?
ثم ماذا فعلت كما رئيسة جمعية المرأة؟
- Tell me. - Hey!
- أخبرني. - يا!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
- We can't fight among ourselves. - He's right.
- لا يمكننا القتال فيما بيننا. - إنه على حق.
Last year people in the next village got into a fight,
الناس في العام الماضي في القرية التالية دخلت في قتال،
then someone put pesticide in the well and everyone died.
ثم قام شخص ما بوضع مبيد حشري في البئر ومات الجميع.
Why the heck are you saying something so horrendous?
لماذا هيك تقول شيء فظيع جدا؟
I'm just saying. Don't mind me.
أنا فقط أقول. لا مانع لي.
Someone's there!
شخص ما هناك!
- What? - Hey!
- ماذا؟ - يا!
Hey! You!
يا! أنت!
What the heck is this?
ما هيك هذا؟
Can't you hear me?
ألا تسمعني؟
- Hey! - Don't mess with my temper...
- يا! - لا تعبثي بأعصابي..
What? A woman?
ماذا؟ امرأة؟
Her stomach... She's pregnant too.
بطنها... وهي حامل أيضاً.
Did you bring this to shoot her?
هل أحضرت هذا لتطلق النار عليها؟
No, I didn't.
لا، لم أفعل.
- You rat. - Goodness.
- أيها الجرذ. - الخير.
Hey, I'm pregnant too!
مهلا، أنا حامل أيضا!
I just gave birth to my kid too!
لقد أنجبت للتو طفلي أيضًا!
That's wonderful news!
هذه أخبار رائعة!
Then our children will be the same age.
ثم سيكون أطفالنا في نفس العمر.
It'll be wonderful to see them grow, play, and go to school together.
سيكون من الرائع رؤيتهم ينمون، اللعب والذهاب إلى المدرسة معًا.
Hey, you're right.
مهلا، أنت على حق.
Gum-ja, when are you due this month?
جوم جا، متى موعد ولادتك هذا الشهر؟
- Less than half a month. - What?
- أقل من نصف شهر. - ماذا؟
Goodness, really?
الخير، حقا؟
I hope it's a son this time.
آمل أن يكون ابنا هذه المرة.
She's having a son!
لديها ابنا!
- What?
- ماذا؟
I went to this famous fortune-teller,
ذهبت إلى هذا العراف الشهير،
and this time, she's having a son.
وهذه المرة، لديها ولدا.
- Really? - My goodness!
- حقًا؟ - يا إلهي!
She's really having a son?
هل لديها ابن حقا؟
- My goodness, this is wonderful! - She is!
-إلهي، هذا رائع! - هي!
This is great news!
هذه أخبار عظيمة!
Congratulations.
تهانينا.
I should butcher a pig.
يجب أن أذبح خنزيراً.
- Sounds great! - Yes, pork is a must for feasts!
- يبدو عظيما! - نعم، لحم الخنزير ضروري في الأعياد!
- Yes. - Goodness.
- نعم. - الخير.
- I want some boiled pork. - Wait!
- أريد بعض لحم الخنزير المسلوق. - انتظر!
We don't know if your kid and my kid will go to school together.
نحن لا نعرف ما إذا كان طفلك و سوف يذهب طفلي إلى المدرسة معًا.
Because you can't run a pig farm in this village.
لأنك لا تستطيع الركض مزرعة خنازير في هذه القرية.
- Why not? - Why do you think?
- ولم لا؟ - لماذا تعتقد؟
We'll keep filing civil complaints to stop you.
سنستمر في تقديم الشكاوى المدنية لإيقافك.
And what if the pig catches some contagious disease?
وماذا لو أمسك الخنزير بعض الأمراض المعدية؟
The entire village will get quarantined.
سيتم عزل القرية بأكملها.
We can't live with this inconvenience!
لا يمكننا العيش مع هذا الإزعاج!
Hey.
يا.
I'm the village head.
أنا رئيس القرية.
An unpleasant facility such as a pig farm...
منشأة غير سارة مثل مزرعة الخنازير ...
requires the understanding and agreement of the villagers.
يتطلب الفهم وموافقة أهل القرية.
That's common sense and it's the right thing to do.
هذا هو المنطق السليم و هذا هو الشيء الصحيح الذي ينبغي عمله.
Yes.
نعم.
In that case,
في تلك الحالة،
may I file a civil complaint too?
هل يمكنني تقديم شكوى مدنية أيضًا؟
Pardon?
عفو؟
Your dogs bark all day long, and it's so loud.
كلابك تنبح طوال اليوم، بصوت عالٍ جدًا.
I can't stand it.
لا أستطيع تحمل ذلك.
And you've occupied state-owned land without permission, right?
ولقد احتلت المملوكة للدولة الأرض دون إذن، أليس كذلك؟
State-owned land?
الأراضي المملوكة للدولة؟
You dry pepper on the road!
أنت تجفف الفلفل على الطريق!
It's very inconvenient, trying to avoid stepping on it.
إنه غير مريح للغاية، في محاولة لتجنب الدوس عليه.
And you, the village head. You instigated the villagers...
وأنت يا رئيس القرية. لقد حرضت القرويين...
to vote for a certain candidate.
للتصويت لمرشح معين.
- That's illegal campaigning. - Well...
- هذه حملة غير قانونية. - حسنا...
They can vote for anyone in this democratic country.
يمكنهم التصويت لأي شخص في هذا البلد الديمقراطي.
That's common sense and it's the right thing to do.
هذا هو المنطق السليم و هذا هو الشيء الصحيح الذي ينبغي عمله.
The plastic greenhouse in the forest should be pulled down!
الدفيئة البلاستيكية في ينبغي هدم الغابة إلى أسفل!
It blocks my view of the mountains,
يمنعني من رؤية الجبال
- and it's very inconvenient! - Goodness.
- وهذا غير مريح للغاية! - الخير.
And you, why do you use so much pesticide?
وأنت، لماذا تستخدم الكثير من المبيدات الحشرية؟
What if you damage the land?
ماذا لو ألحقت الضرر بالأرض؟
Why do you care if I damage the land I own?
لماذا تهتم إذا ألحقت الضرر بالأرض التي أملكها؟
You don't own the frogs and loaches that live there!
أنت لا تملك الضفادع واللوش الذي يعيش هناك!
You wench.
أنت بغي.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
- Let her go! - Stop that!
- اسمح لها أن تذهب! - توقف عن ذلك!
That's my husband you're talking to!
هذا هو زوجي الذي تتحدث إليه!
- That's enough! - You people started this!
- هذا يكفي! - أنتم أيها الناس بدأتم هذا!
- Let go! - Goodness!
- اتركه! - الخير!
- No, you let go!
- لا، تركتك!
- Let go! - Stop this!
- اتركه! - أوقف هذا!
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
- What's wrong with her? - What...?
- ما بها؟ - ماذا...؟
Goodness.
الخير.
Are you all right?
هل أنت بخير؟
- Let go of him! - Let go!
- اتركه!
- What are you doing?
- ماذا تفعل؟
Gum-ja!
علكة جا!
- You're making my husband bald! - Let go!
- أنت تجعل زوجي أصلع! - اتركه!
- Stop pulling his hair! - Let go of her!
- توقف عن شد شعره! - اتركها!
Let go!
اتركه!
One second.
ثانية واحدة.
- I think she's about to give birth. - Goodness.
- أعتقد أنها على وشك الولادة. - الخير.
- Oh, no.
- أوه لا.
Goodness, what do we do?
يا إلهي، ماذا نفعل؟
- What's that? - Goodness.
- ما هذا؟ - الخير.
- Her water broke.
- انكسر ماءها.
- We have to hurry. - Wait.
- علينا أن نسرع. - انتظر.
- Yes? - Sung-ae, go boil some water.
- نعم؟ - سونغ آي، اذهبي واغلي بعض الماء.
- Okay. - Gum-ja, go to her room...
- تمام. - جوم جا، اذهبي إلى غرفتها...
and lay out the bedding.
ووضع الفراش.
I'll grab the tools.
سأقوم بالاستيلاء على الأدوات.
- Tools? - Scissors!
- أدوات؟ - مقص!
- Scissors, yes. - Yes.
- مقص، نعم. - نعم.
Move!
يتحرك!
Hey, hop on!
مهلا، قفز!
I called you ages ago! Why the heck aren't you here yet?
لقد اتصلت بك منذ زمن طويل! لماذا هيك ليست هنا بعد؟
No, it's Jou-ri!
لا، إنها جو ري!
What do you mean, Cho Yong-pil? Darn it.
ماذا تقصد يا تشو يونج بيل؟ الرتق.
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
- Please look after Jou-ri... - Hey!
- يرجى الاعتناء بجو-ري... - مهلا!
- ...and the unborn child... - You jerks!
-...والطفل الذي لم يولد بعد... - أيها الحمقى!
Will you take responsibility if something goes wrong?
هل ستتحمل المسؤولية إذا حدث خطأ ما؟
Yes, you're doing well.
نعم، أنت بخير.
Yes, listen to me.
نعم، استمع لي.
You can't clench your stomach.
لا يمكنك الضغط على معدتك.
- Don't do that. - Right.
- لا تفعل ذلك. - يمين.
Think of this as taking a dump,
فكر في هذا كأخذ تفريغ،
- and flex your buttocks. - Okay.
- وثني الأرداف. - تمام.
- Do you understand? - Yes.
- هل تفهم؟ - نعم.
So...
لذا...
are the scissors ready?
هل المقص جاهز؟
I'm coming!
أنا قادم!
It's nice and sharp.
انها لطيفة وحادة.
This is sharp enough to cut down the wood a woodchuck would chuck.
هذا حاد بما يكفي لخفضه الخشب الذي سيقذفه طائر الحطاب.
Goodness.
الخير.
I can never say that right.
لا أستطيع أن أقول هذا الحق أبدا.
Wood a woodchunk would chunk.
الخشب قطعة خشبية سوف قطعة.
No, wood a woodchuck would chuck.
لا، الخشب سوف يلقي ظرف الخشب.
- Woond... - A woodchunk could chunk.
- جرح... - قطعة خشب يمكن أن تكون قطعة.
- Would chunk. - Can you do it?
- هل قطعة. - هل يمكنك أن تفعل ذلك؟
A wood a woodchunk would...
قطعة خشب من شأنها أن...
Wood a woodchuck...
الخشب طائر الحطاب...
- Goodness. - ...would chuck!
- الخير. - ...سوف تشاك!
That's right!
هذا صحيح!
Wood a woodchuck would chuck. You're good!
الخشب سوف يلقي ظرف الخشب. أنت جيدة أو أنت طيب!
Goodness, quiet down.
الخير، اهدأ.
Quiet down.
هادئ.
All of you, hold her hands.
كلكم، أمسكوا يديها.
- Hands. - Right here.
- الأيدي. - هنا.
Here we go.
ها نحن.
One, two, three.
واحد اثنين ثلاثة.
- Push!
- يدفع!
Push!
يدفع!
- Okay, good. - Goodness.
- حسنًا، جيد. - الخير.
You can't relax like this again.
لا يمكنك الاسترخاء بهذه الطريقة مرة أخرى.
You're giving the child a tough time in here.
أنت تعطي الطفل وقتًا عصيبًا هنا.
Think of your child,
فكر في طفلك،
and think of this as the last time.
وفكر في هذه على أنها المرة الأخيرة.
Let's try this one more time with all your energy.
دعونا نجرب هذا أكثر الوقت بكل طاقتك.
One, two, three.
واحد اثنين ثلاثة.
- Push!
- يدفع!
- It's coming! - I see the baby!
- إنها قادمة! - أرى الطفل!
- More!
- أكثر!
You still haven't found us?
هل مازلت لم تجدنا؟
It's right under the persimmon tree!
إنه مباشرة تحت شجرة البرسيمون!
It's next to Gu Ja-yeong's place!
إنه بجوار منزل Gu Ja-yeong!
Hey, you punk. Don't you know who Gu Ja-yeong is?
مهلا، أنت فاسق. لا تفعل ذلك هل تعرف من هو غو جا يونغ؟
You know, his grandpa was our middle-school principal...
كما تعلمون، كان جده مديرة مدرستنا المتوسطة...
- Is the baby here? - Yes!
- هل الطفل هنا؟ - نعم!
The baby's born! I'm hanging up, you stinking punk!
ولد الطفل! أنا شنق، أنت فاسق النتن!
- The baby is here! - The baby's here?
- الطفل هنا! - الطفل هنا؟
- It's here!
- إنها هنا!
The baby is here!
الطفل هنا!
Your mommy is here.
والدتك هنا.
Goodness.
الخير.
My gosh.
يا إلهي.
Kang-ho.
كانغ هو.
"Choi Kang-ho"?
"تشوي كانغ هو"؟
Yes, Kang-ho.
نعم، كانغ هو.
A really competent and strong person.
شخص مختص وقوي حقًا.
I wanted him to be like that, so that's what the name means.
لقد أردته أن يكون هكذا، هذا ما يعنيه الاسم.
- I love it. Kang-ho. - Isn't it nice?
- أنا أحبه. كانغ هو. - أليس لطيفا؟
And Kang-ho isn't just any strong person.
وكانغ هو ليس مجرد شخص قوي.
He's the strongest one.
إنه الأقوى.
- Choi Kang-ho.
- تشوي كانغ هو.
Look.
ينظر.
Kang-ho, it's me, your father.
كانغ هو، هذا أنا، والدك.
Choi Kang-ho.
تشوي كانغ هو.
You have to grow up as a powerful and strong person.
عليك أن تكبر ك شخص قوي وقوي.
Okay?
تمام؟
Okay.
تمام.
He just said yes.
لقد قال نعم للتو.
Honey.
عسل.
He's our Kang-ho.
إنه كانغ هو.
I'll raise him well.
سوف أقوم بتربيته بشكل جيد.
I'll raise him...
سأقوم بتربيته...
to be the strongest man.
ليكون أقوى رجل.
His name is Kang-ho.
اسمه كانغ هو.
So?
لذا؟
So which is it?
إذن ما هو؟
The delivery was successful.
كان التسليم ناجحا.
Which is it?
ما هو؟
A boy.
صبي.
- A boy!
- صبي!
- Goodness. - A boy.
- الخير. - صبي.
- Is he healthy? - Of course!
- هل هو بصحة جيدة؟ - بالطبع!
- Why are you crying?
- لماذا تبكي؟
- What?
- ماذا؟
I'm practicing.
أنا أتدرب.
- I'll also have a son very soon.
- أنا أيضا سأنجب ابنا قريبا جدا.
Goodness, this guy.
الخير، هذا الرجل.
- You surprised us. - You startled me.
- لقد فاجأتنا. - لقد أذهلتني.
- Gosh. - Goodness.
- يا إلهي. - الخير.
- Oh, my. - What?
- يا بلدي. - ماذا؟
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Are you practicing too?
هل تتدرب أيضاً؟
- Stop it. - No, I have a few more days.
- توقف. - لا، لدي بضعة أيام أخرى.
- Right? - Yes.
- يمين؟ - نعم.
What...?
ماذا...؟
- Oh, my. - What?
- يا بلدي. - ماذا؟
Goodness, it must be for real.
الخير، يجب أن يكون حقيقيا.
Mother, you need to come out!
أمي، عليك أن تخرج!
- What's going on? - What do we do?
- ماذا يحدث هنا؟ - ماذا نفعل؟
I can't believe this.
لا أستطيع أن أصدق هذا.
Take this. Hurry.
خذ هذا. عجل.
My goodness.
يا إلهي.
Boil some water.
اغلي بعض الماء.
Get water.
احصل على الماء.
Goodness.
الخير.
- No, stay with me right now. - Hello?
- لا، ابقي معي الآن. - مرحبًا؟
It's the same Cho Yong-pil place.
إنه نفس مكان تشو يونج بيل.
I need your help.
انا بحاجة الى مساعدتكم.
On the same day, same hour, and under the same roof.
في نفس اليوم، نفس الساعة، وتحت نفس السقف.
Goodness.
الخير.
What are the chances?
ما هي الفرص؟
Tell me about it.
أخبرني عن ذلك.
There have never been births like this.
لم تكن هناك ولادة مثل هذه من قبل.
Is this meant to be or fate?
فهل هذا يعني أن يكون أو مصير؟
That's a funny saying.
هذا قول مضحك.
It'll be a huge hit if that comes out in a movie.
ستكون ضربة كبيرة إذا كان ذلك يخرج في فيلم.
Really?
حقًا؟
Anyway, where's your husband?
على أية حال، أين زوجك؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
He went home.
ذهب إلى المنزل.
That son of a gun.
ذلك ابن البندقية.
Mother.
الأم.
- Well, I... - It's fine.
- حسنا، أنا... - لا بأس.
He's a son of a gun.
إنه ابن البندقية.
Son of a gun.
ابن البندقية.
Good, smile.
جيد، ابتسم.
- Goodness.
- الخير.
- There, there.
- هناك، هناك.
We say it's meant to be...
نقول أنه المقصود...
to someone we meet for the first time.
لشخص نلتقي به لأول مرة.
But fate is...
لكن القدر...
what we say to someone who stays with us until the end.
ماذا نقول لشخص يبقى معنا حتى النهاية.
I'm not sure if this is just meant to be or fate,
لست متأكدا إذا كان هذا هو يعني فقط أن يكون أو القدر،
but I hope all these babies who are born in Jou-ri,
لكني آمل أن يكون كل هؤلاء الأطفال الذين ولدوا في جو ري،
including Sam-sik,
بما في ذلك سام سيك،
stay healthy for a very long time,
البقاء بصحة جيدة لفترة طويلة جدًا ،
and be good friends for a long time.
ويكون أصدقاء جيدين لفترة طويلة.
Sam-sik, they're like your younger siblings.
سام سيك، إنهم مثل إخوتك الصغار.
- Sam-sik is... - In that case,
- سام سيك هو... - في تلك الحالة،
are we not kicking out the dirty pig farm?
ألسنا نطرد مزرعة الخنازير القذرة؟
- That little...! - Are we kicking her out?
- هذا القليل...! - هل نطردها؟
Cover your ears.
قم بتغطية أذنيك.
Goodness, look at them.
يا إلهي، أنظر إليهم.
You can't go this time either?
لا يمكنك الذهاب هذه المرة أيضاً؟
I can't believe her.
لا أستطيع أن أصدقها.
You can't skip studying for just one day?
لا يمكنك تخطي المذاكرة ليوم واحد فقط؟
Should I ask your mom...
هل يجب أن أسأل والدتك...
to let you go to the picnic?
للسماح لك بالذهاب إلى النزهة؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I didn't mean to hit you with it.
لم أقصد أن أضربك به
Now it'll reek of pig poop.
الآن سوف تفوح منه رائحة فضلات الخنازير.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Smell this.
رائحة هذا.
No!
لا!
Sam-sik, you jerk!
سام سيك، أيها الأحمق!
Why the heck do you keep bullying Kang-ho?
لماذا بحق الجحيم تستمر في التنمر على كانغ هو؟
Why?
لماذا؟
Why do you like him?
لماذا تحبه؟
All that idiot does is study.
كل ما يفعله هذا الغبي هو الدراسة.
But then...
ولكن بعد ذلك...
he should study hard.
يجب أن يدرس بجد.
He's a loser who doesn't have a dad!
إنه الخاسر الذي ليس لديه أب!
You douchebag!
أنت أيها الغبي!
"Douchebag"?
"الدوش"؟
Who taught you to swear at your friend like that?
من علمك أن تقسم في صديقك من هذا القبيل؟
Where did you learn such foul language?
أين تعلمت مثل هذه اللغة البذيئة؟
That douchebag made fun of me first!
هذا الدوش سخر مني أولاً!
He said I'm a loser with no dad,
قال أنا فاشل بدون أبي
and to get lost because I smell like pig poop!
وأن أضيع لأن رائحتي تشبه رائحة فضلات الخنازير!
Did you just say "douchebag" again?
هل قلت للتو "douchebag" مرة أخرى؟
Encyclopedia The Periodic Table
الموسوعة الجدول الدوري
You don't have to feel ashamed.
ليس عليك أن تشعر بالخجل.
He's not entirely wrong.
انه ليس مخطئا تماما.
You don't have a father,
ليس لديك أب،
and a pig farm does smell like pig poop.
ورائحة مزرعة الخنازير تشبه رائحة فضلات الخنازير.
See your first birthday picture?
ترى صورة عيد ميلادك الأول؟
I put out a stethoscope, money, a microphone,
لقد وضعت سماعة الطبيب، والمال، والميكروفون،
and even your favorite robot toy.
وحتى لعبة الروبوت المفضلة لديك.
But that gavel is what you picked.
لكن تلك المطرقة هي ما اخترته.
Let him say whatever he wants.
دعه يقول ما يريد.
If he insults you, let him.
إذا أهانك فاسمح له.
Once you study hard and become a prosecutor,
بمجرد أن تدرس بجد وتصبح مدعيًا عامًا،
no one will be able to look down on you or bully you.
لن يتمكن أحد من النظر عليك أو الفتوة لك.
That's true power.
هذه هي القوة الحقيقية.
Do you understand?
هل تفهم؟
Is that why I can't go to the school picnic?
هل هذا هو السبب في أنني لا أستطيع الذهاب إلى نزهة المدرسة؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
You can never become successful...
لا يمكنك أن تصبح ناجحاً أبداً..
without sacrifice.
بدون تضحية.
Stop eating if you're full.
توقف عن الأكل إذا كنت ممتلئًا.
You'll get sleepy if you're too full.
سوف تشعر بالنعاس إذا كنت ممتلئًا جدًا.
You got 3 wrong out of 100.
لقد حصلت على 3 خطأ من 100.
Correct your mistakes and solve the problems until page 130.
صحح أخطائك و حل المسائل حتى الصفحة 130.
Autumn Picnic Announcement
إعلان نزهة الخريف
Please Fill Out Below Grade 4
يُرجى ملء البيانات أدناه الصف الرابع
Reason for Absence
سبب الغياب
Bad Mom
الأم السيئة
I'm home!
أنا في المنزل!
It's Grandma's favorite, meat pancakes!
إنها فطائر اللحم المفضلة لدى الجدة!
Don't touch it before the memorial service.
لا تلمسها قبل حفل التأبين.
This one is torn.
هذا واحد ممزق.
You can't serve a piece like this.
لا يمكنك تقديم قطعة مثل هذه.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Mom, are you crying?
أمي، هل تبكي؟
Crazy brat.
شقي مجنون.
I'm not crying.
أنا لا أبكي.
Darn it. The smoke is getting in my eyes.
الرتق. الدخان يدخل في عيني.
Dad!
أب!
What's with you?
ماذا بك؟
- Come on out! - Let go of me!
- هيا خارجا! - اتركني!
Or I'll report this bar for opening during the day.
أو سأبلغ عن هذا الشريط الافتتاح خلال النهار.
Goodness.
الخير.
Jennifer, you're becoming a better dancer each day.
جنيفر، أنت تصبح راقصة أفضل كل يوم.
You're flattering me.
أنت تملقني.
- Please sit. - Thank you.
- من فضلك اجلس. - شكرًا لك.
Have some.
احصل على بعض.
My goodness!
يا إلهي!
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Dad.
أب.
What?
ماذا؟
Good grief.
حزن جيد.
Let go, you brat.
اترك أيها الشقي.
If you don't want to die on the same day Grandma passed,
إذا كنت لا تريد أن تموت في نفس اليوم الذي ماتت فيه جدتي
you'd better come out.
من الأفضل أن تخرج.
Do you want one?
هل تريد واحدة؟
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Mi-joo!
مي جو!
I'll be home before the sun sets!
سأعود إلى المنزل قبل غروب الشمس!
Red fruit on the right, white fruit on the left!
فاكهة حمراء على اليمين وفاكهة بيضاء على اليسار!
Dried fish on the left, sikhye on the right!
السمك المجفف على اليسار، سيخي على اليمين!
♫ Call me, call me, call, call, give a call ♫
♫ اتصل بي، اتصل بي، اتصل، اتصل، اتصل ♫
They're so pretty!
إنهم جميلون جدًا!
♫ If you want my heart, I'll give it to you ♫
♫ إذا كنت تريد قلبي، سأعطيك إياه ♫
♫ Just like this, your love is ♫
♫ تمامًا هكذا، حبك ♫
♫ all for me ♫
♫ كل شيء من أجلي ♫
♫ I'll give you my heart ♫
♫ سأعطيك قلبي ♫
Isn't it enough that Dad's out dancing?
ألا يكفي أن أبي بالخارج يرقص؟
Do you have to do this nonsense?
هل عليك أن تفعل هذا الهراء؟
What's with you?
ماذا بك؟
- Stop dancing! - Why should I?
- توقف عن الرقص! - لماذا ينبغي لي؟
Where's this darned little brat?
أين هذا الشقي الصغير اللعين؟
Lee Mi-joo!
لي مي جو!
Hey, you brat!
مهلا، أنت شقي!
Why do you keep doing this to my hand?
لماذا تستمر في فعل هذا بيدي؟
What's that?
ما هذا؟
Is she eating gimbap?
هل تأكل الكيمباب؟
Oh, my.
يا بلدي.
You brat! You little...!
أنت شقي! أيها الصغير...!
That was for your school trip!
كان ذلك لرحلتك المدرسية!
Stop right there, you brat!
توقف هناك أيها الشقي!
I missed the shot.
لقد فاتني اللقطة.
Hey! Pass!
يا! يمر!
- Pass! - You're so handsome!
- يمر! - أنت وسيم جدا!
Pass!
يمر!
I root for the winning team!
أنا أشجع الفريق الفائز!
You're so good-looking!
أنت حسن المظهر!
Pass.
يمر.
- Go! - Let's go!
- يذهب! - دعنا نذهب!
Oh, my!
يا بلدي!
I knew you'd be here.
كنت أعرف أنك ستكون هنا.
How did you know...?
كيف عرفت...؟
You'd always disappear during lunch and dinner,
كنت تختفي دائمًا أثناء الغداء والعشاء،
so I tailed you for a few days.
لذلك قمت بتعقبك لبضعة أيام.
Right.
يمين.
Here, it's your present.
هنا، إنها هديتك.
I mean, you've never been on a school picnic or trip,
أعني أنك لم تكن أبدا في نزهة مدرسية أو رحلة،
so you probably never had a chance to eat gimbap.
لذلك ربما لن تفعل ذلك أبدًا أتيحت لي الفرصة لتناول الكيمباب
I wondered what I should get you for your birthday,
تساءلت ماذا يجب أن أفعل احضر لك عيد ميلادك,
then thought of this.
ثم فكرت في هذا.
- For my birthday? - Today's your birthday.
- في عيد ميلادي؟ - اليوم عيد ميلادك.
And my birthday too.
وعيد ميلادي أيضا.
Goodbye, Choi Kang-ho.
وداعا، تشوي كانغ هو.
Good luck.
حظ سعيد.
Why are you picking out the carrots?
لماذا تختار الجزر؟
I don't like carrots.
أنا لا أحب الجزر.
Really?
حقًا؟
Kang-ho doesn't like carrots. Noted.
كانغ هو لا يحب الجزر. ذُكر.
Wait, what?
انتظر ماذا؟
- Why don't you have some more? - I'm done.
- لماذا لا يكون لديك بعض أكثر؟ - أنا انتهيت.
You only had five pieces. What do you mean?
كان لديك خمس قطع فقط. ماذا تقصد؟
You should have some more.
يجب أن يكون لديك بعض أكثر.
No, it's okay. I can't be full.
لا، لا بأس. لا أستطيع أن أكون ممتلئا.
Why not?
ولم لا؟
I get sleepy when I'm full.
أشعر بالنعاس عندما أكون ممتلئًا.
If I'm sleepy, I can't study.
إذا كنت نعسانًا، فلا أستطيع الدراسة.
If I don't study, I can't become a prosecutor.
إذا لم أدرس، لا أستطيع أن أصبح مدعياً ​​عاماً.
That's nonsense.
هذا هراء.
Right? It does sound like nonsense.
يمين؟ يبدو الأمر وكأنه هراء.
Like our names, zodiac signs, and blood types,
مثل أسمائنا، وعلامات الأبراج، وفصائل الدم،
I thought everyone was born under a specific job.
اعتقدت أن الجميع كانوا كذلك ولد تحت وظيفة محددة.
So when I saw kids switching dreams every semester,
لذلك عندما رأيت الأطفال يتحولون أحلام كل فصل دراسي
- I thought they were ridiculous. - Right.
- اعتقدت أنهم كانوا سخيفين. - يمين.
But it turns out, I was the ridiculous one.
لكن اتضح أنني كنت الشخص السخيف.
If you don't like that, it's not too late to do what you want.
إذا كنت لا تحب ذلك، فهو كذلك لم يفت الأوان بعد لفعل ما تريد.
What I want?
ماذا أريد؟
Yes.
نعم.
What is that?
ما هذا؟
Come to think about it, I've never thought about that.
تعال للتفكير في الأمر، لم أفكر قط في ذلك.
Kang-ho, you poor thing.
كانغ هو، أيها المسكين.
That's the bell. Let's go for our night study.
هذا هو الجرس. دعنا نذهب لدراستنا الليلية.
Okay.
تمام.
What do we do?
ماذا نفعل؟
I think it's locked.
أعتقد أنه مقفل.
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
- Hello?
- مرحبًا؟
- Hello? Hey!
- مرحبًا؟ يا!
- We're in here. - Hey!
- نحن هنا. - مهلا!
Darn it.
الرتق.
Hey! We're in here!
يا! نحن هنا!
Is anybody out there?
هل يوجد أحد هناك؟
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Kang-ho.
كانغ هو.
That's enough.
هذا يكفي.
Uri High School
مدرسة أوري الثانوية
Food for the Brain
غذاء الدماغ
We're All Jou-ri Family
كلنا عائلة جو-ري
What on earth is going on?
ماذا يحدث بحق السماء؟
These kids never caused any trouble. What's happening?
هؤلاء الأطفال لم يسببوا أبدا أي مشكلة. ماذا يحدث؟
Was he acting differently lately?
هل كان يتصرف بشكل مختلف في الآونة الأخيرة؟
No, not at all.
لا، على الاطلاق.
Oh, right.
أوه، صحيح.
Mi-joo took gimbap when she left this morning.
أخذت مي-جو الكيمباب عندما غادرت هذا الصباح.
- Gimbap? - Yes.
- جيمباب؟ - نعم.
Maybe they went to hang out at Bongil Stream.
ربما ذهبوا للتسكع في Bongil Stream.
Tomorrow is the midterm. He wouldn't do that.
غدا هو منتصف المدة. لن يفعل ذلك.
The midterm is tomorrow?
منتصف المدة غدا؟
Good grief, that little brat.
حزن جيد، ذلك الشقي الصغير.
This is bad.
هذا سيء.
It won't be good if high-school kids end up having a child.
لن يكون الأمر جيدًا إذا كنت في المدرسة الثانوية ينتهي الأمر بالأطفال إلى إنجاب طفل.
Hey! Watch what you say!
يا! انتبه لما تقوله!
She's quite unwell. Please try to understand.
انها ليست على ما يرام تماما. من فضلك حاول أن تفهم.
I'm unwell?
أنا مريض؟
Sam-sik.
سام سيك.
- Sam-sik! - Sam-sik, are you in?
- سام سيك! - سام سيك، هل أنت هنا؟
- The lights turned on. - The lights.
- أضاءت الأضواء. - الأضواء.
- Goodness. - My gosh.
- الخير. - يا إلهي.
Gosh, I'm sorry.
يا إلهي، أنا آسف.
Why are you here at this ungodly hour?
لماذا أنت هنا في هذه الساعة الشريرة؟
Kang-ho and Mi-joo are missing.
كانغ هو ومي جو مفقودان.
Kang-ho's missing?
كانغ هو مفقود؟
Mi-joo too?
مي جو أيضا؟
Wait, Mi-joo was in there too?
انتظر، مي جو كانت هناك أيضًا؟
In there? Where?
هناك؟ أين؟
- What do you mean? - Nothing.
- ماذا تقصد؟ - لا شئ.
- Mom, move. - Sam-sik!
- أمي، تحركي. - سام سيك!
- Hey!
- يا!
Where are you going? We came down that way!
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟ لقد نزلنا بهذه الطريقة!
No!
لا!
Do we have to stay here all night?
هل علينا البقاء هنا طوال الليل؟
Why do they make us turn in our cell phones?
لماذا يجبرونا على تسليم هواتفنا المحمولة؟
Everyone must be freaking out now.
لا بد أن الجميع يشعرون بالذعر الآن.
I'm hungry. Do we have food?
أنا جائع. هل لدينا طعام؟
I found candy.
لقد وجدت الحلوى.
- Kang-ho, I'll give you half. - It's okay.
- كانغ هو، سأعطيك النصف. - لا بأس.
I don't like candy.
أنا لا أحب الحلوى.
You dislike a lot of things.
أنت لا تحب الكثير من الأشياء.
It's okay.
لا بأس.
I only need you to like me.
أنا فقط بحاجة لك أن تحبني.
Okay?
تمام؟
Hey! Think about it.
يا! فكر في الأمر.
You're locked up in this place with a girl.
أنت محتجز في هذا المكان مع فتاة.
All you can do is study?
كل ما يمكنك فعله هو الدراسة؟
What about me? Pay some attention to me.
ماذا عني؟ انتبه لي بعض الشيء.
"Perhaps love is as such."
"ربما يكون الحب هكذا."
Love?
حب؟
"Like a rain shower, it suffocates me..."
"مثل زخات المطر، تخنقني..."
"from the head and covers me."
"من رأسي ويغطيني".
That rain shower is a simile.
هذا الدش المطري هو تشبيه.
It might be on the exam tomorrow.
قد يكون في الامتحان غدا.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
I'm going to lose weight, become pretty, and marry into a good family.
سوف أفقد الوزن، أصبح جميلة، وتتزوج في عائلة جيدة.
I can do it.
أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك.
All you do is study.
كل ما تفعله هو الدراسة.
Who cares if you get all As?
من يهتم إذا حصلت على كل شيء؟
You're an F when it comes to social cues.
أنت حرف F عندما يتعلق الأمر بالإشارات الاجتماعية.
Hey, what's wrong?
مهلا، ما هو الخطأ؟
Are you choking on the candy?
هل تختنق بالحلوى؟
This isn't good. Come here.
هذا ليس جيدًا. تعال الى هنا.
Spit it out on three.
بصقها على ثلاثة.
One, two, three.
واحد اثنين ثلاثة.
Again. One, two, three!
مرة أخرى. واحد اثنين ثلاثة!
Three! Again.
ثلاثة! مرة أخرى.
One, two, three!
واحد اثنين ثلاثة!
You jerk!
أنت رعشة!
Goodness.
الخير.
Sam-sik.
سام سيك.
Why did you push him so hard?
لماذا ضغطت عليه بشدة؟
Are you all right?
هل أنت بخير؟
How long have you been here?
منذ متى وأنت هنا؟
Did you miss your supplementary class?
هل فاتتك صفك التكميلي؟
Key Points of "At the End of Cicada's Cry"
النقاط الرئيسية في "في نهاية صرخة الزيز"
I'm sorry for causing trouble at this hour.
أنا آسف لتسببي في مشكلة في هذه الساعة.
You.
أنت.
I was worried sick about you.
لقد كنت قلقة عليك.
Goodness, it's all right.
يا إلهي، كل شيء على ما يرام.
It's fine. Nothing bad happened.
لا بأس. لم يحدث شيء سيء.
They're both clothed. Nothing happened.
كلاهما يرتديان الملابس. لم يحدث شيء.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Get your backpack.
احصل على حقيبة الظهر الخاصة بك.
Let's go. We'll talk at home.
دعنا نذهب. سنتحدث في المنزل.
I...
أنا...
She's so intense.
انها مكثفة جدا.
How could she worry about the supplementary class in this situation?
كيف يمكن أن تقلق بشأن الصف التكميلي في هذه الحالة؟
Goodness, she's a great woman.
يا إلهي، إنها امرأة عظيمة.
But why is she so harsh to her son?
ولكن لماذا هي قاسية جدا مع ابنها؟
That's why Kang-ho grew up so well.
لهذا السبب نشأ كانغ هو بشكل جيد.
He's never caused any trouble,
فهو لم يسبب أي مشكلة أبداً
and he's the top student in the country.
وهو الطالب الأول في البلاد.
Shut up.
اسكت.
Well, I guess it'll be great...
حسنًا، أعتقد أنه سيكون رائعًا..
if he studies hard and goes into law.
إذا درس بجد ودخل في القانون.
What's so good about that?
ما الجيد في ذلك؟
To be frank, people here could live an honest life even without the law.
لأكون صريحًا، يمكن للناس هنا أن يعيشوا حياة صادقة حتى بدون القانون.
Not everyone.
ليس الجميع.
Sam-sik is an exception.
سام سيك استثناء.
- Gosh. - What?
- يا إلهي. - ماذا؟
You cursed woman!
أيتها المرأة الملعونة!
- You and your mouth! - Come on.
- أنت وفمك! - تعال.
Let's go. It's late. Come with me.
دعنا نذهب. إنه متأخر. تعال معي.
How could she say that?
كيف يمكنها أن تقول ذلك؟
You darn punk.
أنت فاسق الرتق.
How could you lock up your friends?
كيف يمكنك حبس أصدقائك؟
Do you want to be expelled from school?
هل تريد أن تطرد من المدرسة؟
I don't care about school,
لا أهتم بالمدرسة،
but can you cut off my hands?
ولكن هل تستطيع أن تقطع يدي؟
What have I done?
ماذا فعلت؟
You darn punk.
أنت فاسق الرتق.
Are you trying to disgrace your mother and father?
هل تحاول العار والدتك وأبوك؟
You have exams tomorrow, so I didn't make seaweed soup.
غدا لديك امتحانات لذلك لم أعد حساء الأعشاب البحرية.
I'll make it after the exams.
سأقوم بذلك بعد الامتحانات
I had...
كان لي...
gimbap earlier.
غيمباب سابقًا.
All right.
حسنًا.
You'll be sleepy if you're full.
سوف تشعر بالنعاس إذا كنت ممتلئًا.
Finish your studies and go to bed.
أنهي دراستك واذهب إلى السرير.
2007 College Entrance Exam
اختبار القبول في الكلية لعام 2007
Do Well on the Exam Conquer Your Exam
أحسن أداءك في الامتحان قهر الامتحان الخاص بك
Don't be nervous.
لا تكن عصبيا.
Do as you've always done.
افعل كما فعلت دائمًا.
Read your questions thoroughly and manage your time well.
إقرأ أسئلتك جيداً وإدارة وقتك بشكل جيد.
Right.
يمين.
Don't eat too much for lunch.
لا تأكل كثيرا على الغداء.
You'll get sleepy during the listening test.
سوف تشعر بالنعاس أثناء اختبار الاستماع.
Okay.
تمام.
- Good luck! - You'll do well!
- حظ سعيد! - سوف تفعل جيدا!
Kang-ho.
كانغ هو.
- Kang-ho. - Good luck!
- كانغ هو. - حظ سعيد!
- Kang-ho, over here. - Please move your car.
- كانغ هو، هنا. - من فضلك تحرك سيارتك.
- All right, I will. - Good luck!
- حسنًا، سأفعل. - حظ سعيد!
- Kang-ho!
- كانغ هو!
Kang-ho!
كانغ هو!
You came? You're already admitted.
جئت؟ لقد تم قبولك بالفعل.
I came to show support for my boyfriend.
جئت لإظهار الدعم لصديقي.
Oh, my. Did I just say boyfriend?
يا بلدي. هل قلت للتو صديقها؟
How silly of me.
كم هو سخيف مني.
Give me your hand.
أعطني يدك.
What?
ماذا؟
Stay still, okay?
ابقَ ساكنًا، حسنًا؟
I read your horoscope today,
قرأت برجك اليوم
and the lucky color is yellow for the Year of the Dragon.
واللون المحظوظ هو الأصفر لعام التنين.
So here.
إذن هنا.
How pretty.
كم هي جميلة.
There.
هناك.
I colored my nails too.
لقد قمت بتلوين أظافري أيضًا.
And these.
وهذه.
This is a fork so you can pick the correct answers.
هذه شوكة حتى تتمكن من ذلك اختر الإجابات الصحيحة.
And a roll of toilet paper. You'll be on a roll.
ولفة من ورق التواليت. عليك أن تكون على لفة.
And this, a tambourine.
وهذا، الدف.
Do well!
أحسنت!
Hey.
يا.
And here's the highlight.
وهنا أبرز.
Gimbap.
غيمباب.
After the exam,
بعد الامتحان،
you're going to eat as much as you want.
سوف تأكل بقدر ما تريد.
And you've never been to the movies or to karaoke, so we're doing that too.
وأنت لم تذهب إلى السينما قط أو الكاريوكي، لذلك نحن نفعل ذلك أيضا.
You're allowed to do that today, right?
مسموح لك أن تفعل ذلك اليوم، أليس كذلك؟
- Yes. - Good.
- نعم. - جيد.
I'll be praying for you, and I'll stick around until the end.
سأدعو لك، و سوف أبقى هنا حتى النهاية.
Kang-ho, get it!
كانغ هو، احصل عليه!
Go...
اذهب...
- Get it!
- احصل عليه!
And this one too. Go now.
وهذا أيضا. اذهب الآن.
Perfect score, Choi Kang-ho!
نتيجة مثالية، تشوي كانغ هو!
I can't live without you!
لا استطيع العيش بدونك!
Perfect score...
درجة مثالية...
Mi-joo!
مي جو!
Excuse me.
اعذرني.
- What happened? - Mi-joo.
- ماذا حدث؟ - مي جو.
Mi-joo, are you okay?
مي جو، هل أنت بخير؟
Mi-joo, wait... Mi-joo.
مي-جو، انتظري... مي-جو.
Mi-joo, stay with me.
مي-جو، ابقي معي.
Mi-joo!
مي جو!
Finally, today is the day.
وأخيرا، اليوم هو اليوم.
Kang-ho...
كانغ هو...
has studied very hard until this day.
لقد درس بجد حتى يومنا هذا.
Here Rests Choi Hae-sik
هنا يرقد تشوي هاي سيك
You know it better than I do.
أنت تعرف ذلك أفضل مني.
Help him do well on the exam,
ساعديه على النجاح في الامتحان
so the time he spent studying won't be in vain.
وبالتالي فإن الوقت الذي قضاه في الدراسة لن يذهب سدى.
You have to help him, okay?
عليك مساعدته، حسنًا؟
Are you okay, Mi-joo?
هل أنت بخير، مي جو؟
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
- What about the exam? - You can't get up yet.
- وماذا عن الامتحان؟ - لا يمكنك الاستيقاظ بعد.
The exam.
الامتحان.
So?
لذا؟
I can't believe this.
لا أستطيع أن أصدق هذا.
You're crazy.
أنت مجنون.
- No, Mi-joo. - What about the exam?
- لا، مي جو. - وماذا عن الامتحان؟
Mi-joo, it's okay.
مي-جو، لا بأس.
Mi-joo, it's all right.
مي-جو، كل شيء على ما يرام.
It's okay.
لا بأس.
I can take the exam next year.
يمكنني إجراء الامتحان العام المقبل.
- Get out. - Mom.
- اخرج. - أم.
Do I have to pour pig poop on you?
هل يجب علي أن أسكب براز الخنزير عليك؟
Were you the only one there?
هل كنت الوحيد هناك؟
Are you her guardian?
هل أنت ولي أمرها؟
You didn't hit her.
أنت لم تضربها.
Why did you have to miss the exam?
لماذا كان عليك أن تفوت الامتحان؟
You don't realize how important today was?
أنت لا تدرك مدى أهمية اليوم؟
Mom.
أم.
- Mi-joo got hurt. - So what?
- مي جو أصيبت. - وماذا في ذلك؟
- Did she die? - Mom!
- هل ماتت؟ - أم!
Why should you ruin your life because of her?
لماذا يجب أن تدمر حياتك بسببها؟
Why?
لماذا؟
My life?
حياتي؟
Do I have a life?
هل لدي حياة؟
What?
ماذا؟
This is your life.
هذه هي حياتك.
I'm sick and tired of this.
لقد سئمت وتعبت من هذا.
You're suffocating me to death!
أنت تخنقني حتى الموت!
You made a decision over my life and forced it on me.
لقد اتخذت القرار حياتي وفرضتها علي.
Is it my fault that Dad died like that?
هل ذنبي أن أبي مات هكذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Whose fault is it then?
ومن هو الخطأ إذن؟
For what reason did your dad die?
لأي سبب مات والدك؟
I need to know that!
أريد أن أعرف ذلك!
You're sick and tired of this?
هل سئمت وتعبت من هذا؟
You want to run away?
تريد الهرب؟
Then become a prosecutor.
ثم أصبح المدعي العام.
That's your only ticket out...
هذه هي تذكرتك الوحيدة للخروج...
from this disgusting pigsty smell...
من رائحة الخنزير المقززة هذه
and your bad mother.
وأمك السيئة.
You're right.
أنت على حق.
You're...
أنت...
a bad person.
شخص سيء.
Why do I ruin my life because of someone else?
لماذا أدمر حياتي بسبب شخص آخر؟
You taught me to live that way!
لقد علمتني أن أعيش بهذه الطريقة!
You told me to become a powerful man,
لقد أخبرتني أن أصبح رجلاً قوياً
and help those who are weak and in need!
ومساعدة الضعفاء والمحتاجين!
But no.
لكن لا.
You were just...
كنت فقط...
frustrated to live as the weak.
محبط للعيش كالضعفاء.
You just wanted to get that power through me.
لقد أردت فقط الحصول على تلك القوة من خلالي.
You...
أنت...
wanted to raise me into a selfish snob just like those who killed Dad.
أراد أن يرفعني إلى الأنانية متكبر مثل أولئك الذين قتلوا أبي.
Okay, fine.
حسنًا، حسنًا.
I'll do that.
سأفعل ذلك.
Kang-ho has a trial today.
يخضع كانغ هو للمحاكمة اليوم.
Please help him win again.
الرجاء مساعدته على الفوز مرة أخرى.
Please.
من فضلك
Prosecutor
المدعي العام
Prosecutor, request sentencing.
أيها المدعي العام، اطلب الحكم.
Jung Min-ho, the victim, fell and passed away on December 22, 2020...
جونغ مين هو، الضحية، سقط و وافته المنية بتاريخ 22/12/2020...
at the construction site of Woobyeok Stay in Sua-dong,
في موقع البناء إقامة ووبيوك في سوا دونغ،
due to the lack of scaffolding of the exterior railing.
بسبب عدم وجود السقالات من السور الخارجي.
He worked in the uppermost site,
كان يعمل في الموقع العلوي،
but there was no safety equipment available,
ولكن لم تكن هناك معدات السلامة المتاحة،
such as safety belts or nets, which could've saved his life.
مثل أحزمة الأمان أو الشباك، والتي كان من الممكن أن تنقذ حياته
Defendant Park Cheol-su, the CEO of the subcontractor,
المتهم بارك تشول سو، الرئيس التنفيذي للمقاول من الباطن،
ignored the constant request...
تجاهلت الطلب المستمر..
of Woobyeok Construction for safety supervision...
من البناء Woobyeok للإشراف على السلامة...
and installation of safety nets, from the moment the construction began.
وتركيب شبكات الأمان، منذ اللحظة التي بدأ فيها البناء.
Your Honor.
شرفك.
The victim, Jung Min-ho, sought a construction site...
الضحية جونغ مين هو مطلوب موقع بناء ...
to pay for his college just before his school year began,
لدفع تكاليف كليته فقط قبل أن يبدأ عامه الدراسي
but he passed at such a young age.
لكنه توفي في مثل هذه السن المبكرة.
Please consider this injustice,
أرجو أن تنظروا إلى هذا الظلم،
and the seriousness of the crime which the defendant has committed,
وخطورة الجريمة التي ارتكبها المتهم،
and sentence him to three years in prison.
والحكم عليه بالسجن ثلاث سنوات.
The defendant, Park Cheol-su,
المتهم بارك تشول سو
didn't only cause damage to the victim's assets,
لم يتسبب فقط في الإضرار بأصول الضحية
but also irrevocable damage, that is, the death of a laborer.
ولكن أيضًا الضرر غير القابل للإصلاح، أي موت العامل.
Formal adjudication.
الحكم الرسمي.
The defendant is sentenced to three years in prison.
الحكم على المدعى عليه إلى ثلاث سنوات في السجن.
Prosecutor Choi.
المدعي العام تشوي.
I have something to say.
لدي شيء لأقوله.
My husband was threatened.
لقد تعرض زوجي للتهديد.
They pressured him with the schedule as soon as they began.
ضغطوا عليه بال الجدول الزمني بمجرد أن بدأت.
That's why the construction was rushed.
ولهذا السبب تم التعجيل بالبناء.
He demanded more safety nets and scaffolds again and again,
وطالب بمزيد من شبكات الأمان والسقالات مرارا وتكرارا،
but Woobyeok Construction ignored him, using the cost as an excuse.
لكن شركة Woobyeok Construction تجاهلت ذلك له، باستخدام التكلفة كذريعة.
And when the accident happened,
وعندما وقع الحادث
they pinned the blame on him.
ألقوا اللوم عليه.
This is my husband's old phone.
هذا هو الهاتف القديم لزوجي.
There's a recording of a call he had with Woobyeok Construction.
هناك تسجيل لمكالمة هو كان مع Woobyeok Construction.
Why did you bring this important evidence to me and not to your attorney?
لماذا جلبت هذا المهم دليل لي وليس لمحاميك؟
Because the attorney...
لأن المحامي...
works for Woobyeok Construction.
يعمل لدى شركة Woobyeok للإنشاءات.
But you can help him.
ولكن يمكنك مساعدته.
Please.
لو سمحت.
Please help him.
الرجاء مساعدته.
Thank you for plucking up the courage to do this.
شكرا لك على نتف تصل الشجاعة للقيام بذلك.
I'll be in contact.
سأكون على اتصال.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Thank you, Prosecutor Choi.
شكرا لك، المدعي العام تشوي.
Woobyeok Group
مجموعة ووبيوك
This is Choi Kang-ho.
هذا هو تشوي كانغ هو.
Things have become troublesome.
لقد أصبحت الأمور مزعجة.
There you are, Prosecutor Choi.
ها أنت أيها المدعي العام تشوي.
Hello, Chairman Song.
مرحبا، الرئيس سونغ.
The Good Bad Mother
الأم الطيبة السيئة
Do you want to be my son?
{\an8هل تريد أن تكون ابني؟
Don't you have a father?
ليس لديك أب؟
How's our prosecutor doing?
كيف حال المدعي العام لدينا؟
- Tell her I'm not home. - Tell her you're not home?
- أخبرها أنني لست في المنزل. - أخبرها أنك لست بالمنزل؟
I won't apologize.
{\an8لن أعتذر.
Someone like you can never call me "Father."
لا يمكن لشخص مثلك أن يناديني بـ "أبي" أبدًا.
It's more than just that.
الأمر أكثر من مجرد ذلك.
Her social status will change.
سوف تتغير حالتها الاجتماعية.
This is a true home run.
{\an8هذه تجربة حقيقية.
Isn't this what you wanted?
أليس هذا ما أردته؟